VINCENT JOHN CAGAY

me@vjcagay.com • www.linkedin.com/in/vjcagay • www.github.com/vjcagay +81 070 4428 1348 • Tōkyō, Japan

PROFILE

I am an engineer who is highly driven when doing projects with good design (visually and friendly), architecture, and good direction. I helped build scalable web apps from internal tools to products that serves millions of users. Mainly working on front-end, I have lots of experience migrating legacy systems to modern architectures. As a huge proponent of accessibility, I want the apps I build be useful to everyone, abled and disabled alike.

WORK EXPERIENCE

VIRTUSIZE SOFTWARE ENGINEER (FRONT-END, FULL-TIME) | TOKYO, JP | 2019 - 2020

- 1. Rewriting and maintaining the phone size comparison tool for Docomo's online shop (iPhones and Android devices) showing the width, height, and thickness, to help customers visualize the sizes of the device they are wanting to buy. Setup continuous integration for the deployment of this tool to production.
- 2. Writing and maintaining components for Virtusize Design System, which is used by multiple Virtusize applications, including the company's core product
- 3. Rewritten and maintain Virtusize's core product: a tool to help users visualize and choose the perfect size of the garment (and accessories) they want to buy, based on their body size, or an existing item they possess. This tool is embedded into online shops (mainly fashion brands). Works on the frontend side of the product. Also helps in integrating the product into current and new client's online shops.

ASURION K.K. SOFTWARE ENGINEER (FRONT-END, CONTRACT) | TOKYO, JP | 2018 - 2019

- Maintained the application used by customer service representatives in handling customer queries for mobile device insurance (e.g. warranties, factory defects). Rearchitected the application front-end to solve very hard to fix bugs (especially Internet Explorer-related) and make it easier to add more features and development during the takeover from old-school JavaScript to modern TypeScript.
- 2. Wrote UI components that can be imported and used for building several products with specific use-cases (e.g. text fields, date pickers, steppers, alert messages)
- 3. Helped build an application for handling device insurance designed to be used by several insurance companies

SKYARCH NETWORKS SOFTWARE ENGINEER (FRONT-END, CONTRACT) | TOKYO, JP | 2016 - 2018

- 1. Rewrote the company's legacy error reporting system from scratch with newer technologies and better software practices.
 - Rewrote the user interface from scratch enabling better user experience with Vue and TypeScript
 - · Used Apollo to access GraphQL backend API
 - Deployed code to production using AWS CodeCommit, CloudFront, Code Pipeline
 - · Maintained the backend written in Python
 - · Handled real-time notifications with Socket.IO
- 2. Implemented the SSO for the company's internal applications
 - Wrote the user interface with React and TypeScript
 - · Maintained the backend written in Node
 - · Managed employee data with AWS Lambda, RDS, and Cognito
 - Pushed front-end code to AWS S3
- 3. Develop a mobile application for a company client that takes images and upload into their servers
 - Wrote the application in React-Native and TypeScript
 - Handled users via AWS Cognito
 - · Uploaded the images to AWS S3

INFOR PSSC SOFTWARE ENGINEER (FRONT-END, FULL-TIME) | MANILA, PH | 2015 - 2016

Worked on Rhythm, an e-commerce platform and one of the company's core products

- · Wrote the widgets the client can customize to fit with their business with Backbone/Marionette, WebPack, SASS
- · Rewrote the Search Widget from scratch to fix all bugs and issues

SCHOOL IMPROVEMENT NETWORK SOFTWARE ENGINEER (FULL-STACK, FULL-TIME) | CEBU, PH | 2013 - 2015

- 1. Migrated Edivate (formerly named PD360) front-end from Flash to JavaScript
 - · Wrote the user interface with Backbone/Marionette, Require, and LESS
 - Contributed to UI/UX decisions in re/implementing new and existing features

2. Also:

- Rewrote Edivate's backend services from ColdFusion to Node
- · Wrote Node micro-service for other products and deploy in Docker containers
- Wrote internal tool for providing graphical UI to Docker in React and Electron
- · Mentored some interns

EDUCATION

STI COLLEGE CEBU B.S. INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY | CEBU, PH

SKILLS

```
JAVASCRIPT Node • TypeScript • Vue • React • React-Native • Flux • WebPack • SASS/LESS/CSS-in-JS

AWS AppSync • Cognito • Lambda • CodePipeline • CodeCommit • S3 • CloudFront • RDS

DATABASES MySQL • PostreSQL • MongoDB • GraphQL

CI CircleCI • Travis CI • Jenkins

OTHER Git • Docker • Vagrant • Linux • GitHub • GitLab • JIRA • Unit Testing
```

LANGUAGES

ENGLISH fluent
FILIPINO fluent
CEBUANO native
JAPANESE basic

INTERESTS

Typography and UI/UX Mobile and Progressive Web Apps, WebAssembly Web Animation and Accessibility Swift/MacOS/iOS Development Machine Learning, A.I., and Computer Vision